const EconomicsNew = [
  {
    "question": " Consider the following statements regarding Gross Domestic Product:",
    "questionOptions": [
      "It is the sum total of domestic final consumption and investment expenditure plus net of exports and imports",
      "It is the sum total of final domestic consumption and investment expenditure plus exports",
      "It is the sum total of final consumption and investment expenditure plus net of exports and imports",
      "It is the sum total of final consumption and investment expenditure plus exports"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below",
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "sum of final value of all goods and services (consumption and capital) produced in economy. This final output is purchased by household sector, Private sector, government sector, outsiders(export)",
    "options": [
      "1 & 2 only",
      "2 & 3 only",
      "3 & 4 only",
      "1, 2 & 3 only"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If India is experiencing economic growth, then which of the following statements must hold true:",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Real GDP will increase",
      "Nominal GDP will increase",
      "Rate of growth of real GDP will increase",
      "Increase in employment generation"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below",
    "answer": 0,
    "explanation": "Real GDP growth measures growth in quantity and nominal GDP measures growth in value (which includes quantity as well as price). In India GDP is calculated in real GDP.",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "1 & 2 only",
      "2 & 3 only",
      "1 & 4 only"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If a country is experiencing recession, then which of the following must be true",
    "answer": 0,
    "explanation": "change in real GDP is negative then it is a case of recession. If the nominal GDP decreases because of decrease in prices, real GDP may increase. If the growth rate is decreasing, GDP may increase.",
    "options": [
      "Decrease in real GDP",
      "Decrease in nominal GDP",
      "Decrease in rate of growth of GDP",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The National Income of a country  (India) is equal to which of the  following",
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "National Income = Net National Income (NNI) = Net National Product = GNP - Depreciation. before January 2015 NSO was using factor cost to calculate NNP but now it uses Market Prices to calculate NNP",
    "options": [
      "Gross National Product (GNP)",
      "Net National Product at Market Prices",
      "Net National Product at Factor Cost",
      "Income going to the household sector"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements are  true regarding Gross National Income:",
    "questionOptions": [
      "It is the income earned by a  country's Residents ",
      "It is the income earned by a  country's residents and non-residents both",
      "It is calculated at market price by  NSO ",
      "It is equal to GDP plus exports  minus imports"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below",
    "answer": 0,
    "explanation": "GNI is the income earned by Indian residents only whether in India or abroad, not include the income earned by NRIs.\nGNI = GNP = GDP + net factor income from abroad (NFIA)",
    "options": [
      "1 & 3 only",
      "1 & 4 only",
      "2 & 3 only",
      "2, 3 & 4 only"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements: ",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Product taxes and production  taxes both are included as part of  GDP calculation",
      "Net Factor Income from Abroad is  equivalent to net of exports &  imports"
    ],
    "answer": 0,
    "explanation": "NFIA is the income earned by the four factors of production from abroad. In case of NFIA the production happens in abroad but in case of exports the production happens in the domestic country.",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "2 only",
      "Both 1 & 2",
      "Neither 1 nor 2"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below"
  },
  {
    "question": "Welfare of the people of a country is  best represented by which of the  following parameter",
    "answer": 0,
    "explanation": "Since increase in price can increase the NI at MP without increasing the welfare of the people. So, welfare can best be represented by per capita NI at constant MP rather than current MP.",
    "options": [
      "Per capita net national income at constant prices",
      "Per capita net national income at current prices",
      "Per capita GDP at constant prices",
      "Per capita GDP at current prices"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "There is a Chinese company doing  business in India. The profit made by  the company will be part of:",
    "questionOptions": [
      "India’s GDP",
      "China’s GNP"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below",
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "profit is just a part of value of production and hence it will be part of India’s GDP. But this belongs to the person in China who owns the company in India, so it will be part of China’s GNP also\n",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "2 only",
      "Both 1 & 2",
      "Neither 1 nor 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements  regarding Gross National Income  (GNI)/GNP:",
    "questionOptions": [
      "It includes production taxes",
      "It includes transfer payment from  rest of the world"
    ],
    "answer": 0,
    "explanation": "GNP includes production taxes. NFIA does not include free transfer. Factor income means income received in return of something and not free transfer/payment.",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "2 only",
      "Both 1 & 2",
      "Neither 1 nor 2"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following constitutes investment in the economy:",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Production of consumption goods",
      "Production of capital goods",
      "Production of services",
      "Buying and selling of shares"
    ],
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "The value of capital goods produced is defined as investment.\nSo, production of consumption goods and services are not investment. Trading shares is also not investment.",
    "options": [
      "1 & 2 only",
      "2 only",
      "2 & 4 only",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below"
  },
  {
    "question": " Consider the following statements:",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Imported capital equipment are  part of investment in Indian  economy",
      "Capital goods exported out of India  are not part of India’s investment"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below",
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "Investment means the value of capital goods that are going to remain in Indian economy whether it was domestically produced or not. Because it will help in increasing domestic production in future.",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "2 only",
      "Both 1 & 2",
      "Neither 1 nor 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements  could be true for a high savings rate in  an economy:",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Higher investment",
      "Higher consumption",
      "Higher exports"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below",
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "High savings will lead to high investment, also beacuse of low consumption. so it must be exported and it will be higher.",
    "options": [
      "1 & 2 only",
      "1 & 3 only",
      "2 & 3 only",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are part of  gross fixed capital formation:",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Machinery and equipment",
      "Construction of buildings and  other infrastructure",
      "Intellectual property rights"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below",
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "also include Cultivated biological resources, animal resources yielding repeat products and tree, crop and plant resources yielding repeat products. also valuable metals and change in inventory",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "1 & 3 only",
      "2 only",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Despite being a high saving economy,  capital formation may not result in  significant increase in output due to",
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "Higher capital-output ratio mean need high capital to output small, so even in if the capital and investments are high, the output will be small.",
    "options": [
      "weak administrative machinery",
      "illiteracy",
      "high population density",
      "high capital-output ratio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements  regarding Incremental Capital Output  Ratio (ICOR): ",
    "questionOptions": [
      "It shows how efficiently the new  capital is being used to produce  output ",
      "It is the extra unit of capital  required to produce one additional  unit of output ",
      "It is the extra unit of output  produced from one additional unit  of capital ",
      "It is the ratio of change in capital  to change in output "
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "ICOR represents how much extra unit of capital is required to produce one additional unit of output. It basically represents the (inverse of) efficiency of the new capital",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "1 & 2 only",
      "1, 2 & 4 only",
      "1, 3 & 4 only"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below"
  },
  {
    "question": "Capital formation in a country will  lead to which of the following: ",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Increase in ICOR ",
      "Decrease in ICOR ",
      "Economic growth "
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "Capital formation mean production of capital goods. which in fact can produce more in the future, so economic growth.",
    "options": [
      "1 & 3 only",
      "2 & 3 only",
      "3 only",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements: ",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Capital output ratio depends on  governance, quality of labour,  technology etc. ",
      "Economic output increases with  decrease in capital output ratio "
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below",
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "Capital output ratio decreasing means productivity increasing, so economic output will increase.",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "2 only",
      "Both 1 & 2",
      "Neither 1 nor 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For a sustained high growth, which of  the following statements will be true",
    "answer": 0,
    "explanation": "% change in GDP = (Investment % / ICOR). so for higher growth, we require more investment and less ICOR.",
    "options": [
      "Raising the investment by keeping the incremental capital output ratio minimum",
      "Raising the investment and incremental capital output ratio both",
      "Increasing capital output ratio and keeping investment at a constant rate",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If the capacity utilization in the  economy is decreasing then consider  the following statements: ",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Capital to output ratio will  decrease ",
      "Per unit cost of production will  increase "
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below",
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "Since capital utilization is decreasing, so ICOR will increase and per unit cost of production will increase.",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "2 only",
      "Both 1 & 2",
      "Neither 1 nor 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If factories are running at full capacity  utilization, then the marginal  productivity of capital will be",
    "answer": 0,
    "explanation": "If running at full capacity, and we add more capital, it will produce more, so the productivity is positive.",
    "options": [
      "Positive",
      "Negative",
      "Zero",
      "One"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": " If a country’s growth rate is good but there is no corresponding growth in  employment, then which of the  following could be the reasons: ",
    "answer": 0,
    "explanation": "If already existing capital is being utilized better, so the economy will grow, but it need not necessary to produce more jobs.",
    "options": [
      "The growth is coming from better utilization of existing capacity and not because of increase in investment",
      "The growth is coming from increase in investment but not because of better utilization ofexisting capacity",
      "The growth is coming from both as a result of increase in investment and increase in capacity utilization",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Economic growth in a country will  necessarily have to occur if",
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "If capital goods are produced instead of consumption goods, it will lead to more production in the economy, thus economy will grow. Production of capital goods means capital formation.",
    "options": [
      "There is technological progress in the country",
      "There is population growth in the country",
      "There is capital formation in the country",
      "The country's exports are increasing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A country is going through a phase of  industrialization. Which of the  following statements are correct?  ",
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "During industrialization, everything goes up and well.",
    "options": [
      "Capital to labour ratio increases",
      "Productivity of labour increases",
      "Total factor productivity increases",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements are  correct about CPI rural, CPI urban  and CPI combined index: ",
    "questionOptions": [
      "Inflation data is published by  NSO ",
      "The base year is 2011-12 ",
      "It is released for all India and for  states and UTs separately on a  monthly basis "
    ],
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "All are correct.",
    "options": [
      "1 only",
      "2 only",
      "2 & 3 only",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "questionDirection": "Select the correct answer using the code given below"
  }
]

module.exports = EconomicsNew;